Inventory of the Alexandra Andreevna Voronine Yourieff Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Alexandra Andreevna Voronine Yourieff Papers
1910-1999
2003C45
Hoover Institution Archives
79 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 1 framed painting, 1 oversize photograph, 1 motion picture film (33.4 linear feet)
Memoirs, other writings, diaries, correspondence, financial records, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian émigré affairs. Includes papers of W. George Yourieff, husband of Alexandra Yourieff. Also includes material relating to the earlier brief marriage of Alexandra Yourieff in the 1920s to the Norwegian relief worker (subsequently Nazi collaborator) Vidkun Quisling.
Yourieff, Alexandra Andreevna Voronine.
Yourieff, W. George.
Access
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2003
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1905 August 20 Born, Sebastopol
1922 Spring Met Vidkun Quisling
1922 September 10 Married Vidkun Quisling
1923 Abandoned by Quisling in Paris
1924 Brought to Norway, and subsequently sent to Nice, France, by Quisling
1929 Quisling halted correspondence and support; she subsequently traveled to China
1933 Russian Orthodox Archbishop of China annulled her marriage, enabling her to marry Dr. J. P. Ryabin
circa 1936 Second husband J. P. Ryabin died
1936 Married W. George Yourieff, architect and honorary French consul in Tsingtao; Yourieff adopts the son from her second marriage
1947 Yourieff family immigrated to the United States
1993 October 1 Died, Palo Alto, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Alexandra Yourieff was the first wife of Vidkun Quisling, who collaborated in the German conquest of Norway in 1940 and was found guilty of treason and executed after Norway was liberated in 1945. She was 16 when she met and married him in 1922. During their marriage, Quisling was also involved with Maria Paseshnikova, later Maria Quisling. After years of separation, he ceased contact with Alexandra in 1929. She subsequently traveled to China, where she met and married Russian physician J. P. Ryabin. After Ryabin died in an accident, leaving her with their son, she married architect W. George Yourieff. They immigrated to the United States in 1947.
Among the most significant material in the papers is Alexandra's manuscript describing her life with Quisling, which remains unpublished. The manuscript describes her childhood and the history of her family, but concentrates on the period of her relationship with Quisling, 1922–1929. Quisling was a Norwegian military attaché in Petrograd (Saint Petersburg) in 1918–1919, and a close coworker of Fridtjof Nansen while Nansen was performing international relief work in Russia from 1922 to 1926. Quisling was attached to the Norwegian legation in Moscow from 1927 to 1929, the year the manuscript ends. The container list identifies notes, research materials, manuscript drafts, and other items relating to this work as "Writings--Quisling book."
The manuscript tells the story of Alexandra's first meeting and romance with Quisling, which took place in Russia against the backdrop, broadly painted but fully substantiated, of a country devastated by wars, epidemics, and famine. Quisling's relief work, his actions, opinions, and general views, are described by a close and trusted witness. It continues with their life in Oslo from fall 1922 to spring 1923, describing Quisling's efforts to mold his young wife to his own pattern. Considerable space is devoted to covering their close circle of friends and the largely unknown Quisling clan in Norway. After describing their years of separation, the manuscript ends in 1929.
The manuscript also provides information about Quisling's childhood, habits, and idiosyncrasies, as well as vivid close-ups of his brothers and mother, who is shown to be quite different from the portraits depicted by other Quisling biographers. In addition, the text paints fascinating pictures of spontaneous and concerted measures by both individuals and governments to cover up their tracks in the wake of dealings with Quisling. Beyond the Quisling story, it offers firsthand information about prominent figures, including Soviet poet Vladimir Maiakovskii, Max Reinhardt, Isadora Duncan, Arthur Rubinstein, Pablo Picasso, and other celebrities of Paris and Nice from the period 1923–1929.
The collection also includes many papers of W. George Yourieff, and records of his business as architect and builder. Alexandra always regarded herself as an artist, and insisted that dancing had been her true vocation. She developed into a very able painter, so documentation of her artistic activities is also included.
Quisling, Vidkun, 1887-1945.; Russians--China.; Russians--United States.
- W. George Yourieff (Box 1)
  - Day books, 1961-1962 (Folder 1: 1-2)
  - Day books labeled "Diaries"
    - Undated (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 1: 4-5)
    - 1977-1979 (Folder 1: 6)
- Obituary of Antonina Aleksandrovna Yourieff published in The Palo Alto Times, 1959 October 17 (Folder 1: 7)
- Biography of Aleksandr Aleksandrovich Tatarinoff (Antonina Yourieff's brother) (Folder 1: 8)
- W. George Yourieff (Antonina Yourieff's son)--Power of attorney, 1989 (Folder 1: 9)
- Sales agreement for burial lot, Alta Mesa Improvement Company, Palo Alto, California, 1954 October 18 (Folder 1: 10)
- Alta Mesa (cemetery), 1961 (Folder 1: 11)
- Family correspondence
  - General, 1951-1956 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Aleksandr Yourieff (son), 1952-1956 (Folder 1: 13)
- Family photographs, undated (Folder 1: 14)
- Text of address by Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Harvard University, 1978 June 8. (Folder 1: 15)
  Scope and Contents note
  In English and Russian
- Writings--Quisling book. Article on Maria and Vidkun Quisling, 1980 March 28. (Box-folder 2: 1)
  In English and Norwegian
- Family correspondence, 1922, 1956-1959, 1980, 1991, 1997 (Folder 2: 2)
- Alexandra Yourieff death certificate, County of Santa Clara, California, 1993 October 1 (Folder 2: 3)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Diary (looks like day book), 1971 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Business-related material--Building estimates
    - 1958 (Folder 2: 5)
    - 1963 (Folder 2: 6-7)
    - 1966 (Folder 2: 8)
    - 1967 (Folder 2: 9)
    - 1968 (Folder 2: 10)
    - 1969 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Personal taxes, 1956-1958 (Folder 2: 12)
- Photographs of Alexandra Yourieff, undated (Folder 2: 13)
- Writings--Quisling book. Chronology of events, correspondence, and legal documents concerning Alexandra's efforts to get her belongings from Oslo, Norway, 1983 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Folder 3: 2)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company--Appraisal of condominium, 1964 (Folder 3: 3)
- Photocopies of official documents, 1947-1948, 1983 (Folder 3: 4)
- Family correspondence, notes, 1960-1976 (Folder 3: 5-6)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 3: 7)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Day book, 1950 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Notes, 1996 (Folder 3: 9)
- Writings--Quisling book. In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kristen A. Seaver, undated. (Box-folder 4: 1)
  Typescript
- Correspondence, 1953-1988 (Folder 4: 2)
- Correspondence, notes, legal documents, photos, 1947-1975 (Folder 4: 3)
- Statements, 1944-1988. (Folder 4: 4)
  Photographic prints
- Children's magazine Lastochka, 1940 (Folder 4: 5)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Contract between W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver, 1981 July 22 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Yourieff, Alexandra--Claims, 1980-1981 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Transcripts of tapes by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, book #1, 1975. (Folder 4: 8)
    In Russian
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, 1987 (Folder 4: 9)
- Correspondence (in Russian and Chinese), business cards, photographs, 1945-1988. (Folder 4: 10)
  Includes clippings about Vidkun Quisling, in Norwegian, 1986
- Miscellany, 1948, 1996 (Folder 4: 11-12)
- Writings--Quisling book. In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver, undated. (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
  Bound typescripts
- Two photos of Alexandra's artwork(?), undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Writings--Quisling book.
  Transcripts of tapes by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff. In Russian
  - Unnumbered, undated (Folder 6: 2)
  - Book #2, taped in 1975 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Book #3, taped in 1975 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Book #6, taped in 1975 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Book #7, taped in 1975 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Book #8, taped in 1975 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Drafts, notes, 1980-1983 (Folder 6: 8-11)
- Financial documents--Barclays (bank), 1984-1988 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1983-1988 (Folder 7: 2)
  - 1979-1982, 1987 (Folder 7: 3)
- W. George Yourieff--Business papers, correspondence with Santa Clara County, 1980-1995 (Folder 7: 4)
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company, 1969-1973(?) (Folder 7: 5)
- Braginsky, Klora and Mikhail, 1983 (Folder 7: 6)
- Correspondence with Martine Yourieff, 1991-1992 (Folder 7: 7)
- Writings--Quisling book. Letter from the Quisling archive at the University of Oslo library regarding Maria Quisling's diary, 1980. (Folder 7: 8)
  Translated by Kirsten A. Seaver. Includes correspondence
- Correspondence between Alexandra Yourieff and Galie Wheen, stop-payment request, 1986, 1988 (Folder 7: 9)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Correspondence between Alexandra Yourieff and M. Dahl-Hansen regarding Quisling estate and probate, 1980-1981 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Alexandra Yourieff notes from diary, 1950-1951 (Folder 7: 11)
- Legal documents from Oslo municipal court, 1983. (Folder 7: 12)
  Translated by Kirsten A. Seaver
- Correspondence between W. George Yourieff and French embassy in China, 1949-1950 (Folder 7: 13)
- Family correspondence, 1965, 1988 (Folder 7: 14)
- Notes, miscellany, undated (Folder 7: 15)
- Photo album, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Photocopies of material published in Norway about Quisling, 1988 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Arve Juritzen, The Private Quisling and His Two Women, 1988. (Folder 8: 3)
    Translated by Kirsten A. Seaver. Typescript
- Drafts of personal and confidential correspondence
  - 1981-1982 (Folder 8: 4)
  - 1981-1983 (Folder 8: 5)
  - 1981 (Folder 8: 6)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Transcripts of tapes by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, book # 9, 1975. (Folder 8: 7)
  - Translation of Alexandra A. Yourieff manuscript, 1983. (Folder 8: 8)
    In English
- Correspondence, 1945-2000. (Box-folder 9: 1)
  Chiefly greeting cards
- Photographs, undated (Folder 9: 2)
- Russian lyrics, undated (Folder 9: 3)
- Writings--Quisling book
  - Letter from Kirsten A. Seaver to a lawyer in Norway, 1983. (Folder 9: 4)
    In Norwegian
  - Photocopies from Norwegian newspapers about the Vidkun Quisling family (Folder 9: 5)
- Drafts of letters from Acia, undated (Folder 9: 6)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Diary labeled "Daily Book,", 1978-1980 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Desk calendar, 1989 (Folder 9: 8)
  - Address book labeled "Daily diary,", 1993 (Folder 9: 9)
  - Business-related papers, 1981-1985 (Folder 9: 10)
- Photographs, 35mm slides, negatives, undated. (Box-folder 10: 1-5)
  Includes photos of art show by Alexandra Yourieff
- Photographs, 35mm slides, negatives, undated. (Box-folder 11: 1-7)
  Also includes flash cards to learn Chinese
- Newspaper Russkaia mysl', Paris, 1988 May 6 (Box-folder 12: 1)
- Bank documents, 1965, 1982. (Folder 12: 2)
  Includes letter from George Yourieff to Hanna M. Meidell, copy of Alexandra Quisling Norwegian passport, notes, two photographs, miscellany
- Writings--Quisling book. Cables, correspondence, 1975, 1978-1979. (Folder 12: 3)
  Includes clippings from Norwegian newspapers and excerpts from the book about Alexandra's journey to Norway
- W. George Yourieff Construction Company, 1951-1957 (Folder 12: 4)
- Photographs of Alexandra's paintings, undated (Folder 12: 5)
- Alexandra Yourieff obituaries, 1993 October 1; duplicate of money transaction from Yourieff family to Norway, 1983 (Folder 12: 6)
- Copy of deposit to the Suisse Bank, 1984 (Folder 12: 7)
- Photographs, prayer, newspaper copy, undated (Folder 12: 8)
- Photocopy of poems written by Yourieff's family member in 1865 (Folder 12: 9)
- Draft manuscript, 1984 (Box-folder 13: 1)
- Notes, 1988 (Folder 13: 2)
- Notes, drafts of letters, 1995 (Folder 13: 3)
- Calculation of expenses, 1995 (Folder 13: 4)
- Lapsed documents (Alexandra's), 1978-1980 (Folder 13: 5)
- Photos, 35mm slides, negatives, undated (Folder 13: 6)
- Family correspondence, 1949-1957 (Folder 13: 7)
- Greeting cards, 1983-1992 (Folder 13: 8)
- Class notes, undated. (Folder 13: 9)
  In French
- Photographs and correspondence, 1971, 1992, undated (Box-folder 14: 1-4)
- Arsene George Yourieff (Box 15)
  - Term paper, City College of San Francisco, 1950 January (Folder 15: 1)
  - Class notes, 1953 (Folder 15: 2)
- Correspondence, 1959, and photograph, 1949. (Folder 15: 3)
  Includes copy of Alexandra Yourieff's California driver license
- W. George Yourieff--Study notes, undated (Folder 15: 4)
- Mother's letters (Antonina Yourieff)
  - 1949-1950 (Folder 15: 5)
  - 1950-1962 (Folder 15: 6)
- Family correspondence, 1954-1965 (Folder 15: 7)
- Writings--Quisling book. In Quisling's Shadow: The Memoirs of His First Wife, by Alexandra Voronine Quisling Yourieff with W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver, chapter 1-5. (Folder 15: 8)
- Class notes, undated (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
- Diary, 1948 (in Russian); Day book, undated (Folder 16: 3)
- Photographs, correspondence, clippings, 1960-1961, undated (Folder 16: 4)
- W. George Yourieff--Day books (Box 17)
  - 1958 (Folder 17: 1-2)
  - 1963 (Folder 17: 3)
  - 1964 (Folder 17: 4-5)
  - 1965 (Folder 17: 6)
  - 1969 (Folder 17: 7)
  - 1973 (Folder 17: 8)
  - 1974 (Folder 17: 9)
- Letters from Wova to Alexandra and W. George Yourieff, 1951-1956 (Folder 17: 10)
- Galie's letters to Alexandra and W. George Yourieff, 1956-1961 (Folder 17: 11)
- Miscellany, 1953-1954 (Folder 17: 12)
- W. George Yourieff (Box 18)
  - Dairies (look like Day books)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 18: 1)
    - 1959-1960 (Folder 18: 2)
    - 1960-1962 (Folder 18: 3)
    - 1962-1963 (Folder 18: 4)
    - 1965-1966 (Folder 18: 5)
  - Prospects (look like Day books)
    - #7, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - #8, 1971-1973 (Folder 18: 7)
  - Yourieff Associates--Job-related notes, 1964 (Folder 18: 8-9)
  - Day books
    - 1974 (Folder 18: 10)
    - 1975 (Folder 18: 11)
    - 1976 (Folder 18: 12)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1985-1995 (Folder 19: 3)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Day books labeled as diaries
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 19: 4)
    - 1969-1970 (Folder 19: 5)
  - Business-related material, undated (Folder 19: 6)
- Writings--Quisling book (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, notes, contract, 1997, undated. (Folder 20: 1)
    Contract is between W. George Yourieff and Kirsten A. Seaver
  - In Quisling's Shadow--Unsorted material, 1960-1980 (Folder 20: 2)
- Yourieff family history collected and written by W. George Yourieff, undated (Folder 20: 3)
- Letters to Galie from Alexandra and W. George, 1952-1965 (Folder 20: 4)
- Family correspondence, 1955-1980 (Folder 20: 5)
- Painting, notes, copy of Alexandra's Norwegian passport, 1937 (Folder 20: 6)
- Photo album, undated (Folder 20: 7)
- Photographs, undated. (Folder 20: 8)
  Includes photos of young Alexandra and Vidkun Quisling
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 20: 9)
- Correspondence, 1950-1991 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- W. George Yourieff--Day books labeled as diaries
  - 1972-1973 (Folder 21: 2)
  - 1973-1975 (Folder 21: 3)
  - 1975-1977 (Folder 21: 4)
  - 1994 (Folder 21: 5)
- W. George Yourieff--Prospects, 1973-1978 (Folder 21: 6)
- Miscellany, 1998 (Folder 21: 7)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 21: 8-9)
- Correspondence (Box 22)
  - Zhenia, 1946-1951 (Folder 22: 1)
  - Asia-Arsik, 1949 (Folder 22: 2)
  - Shura, 1949-1961 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Other personal correspondence, 1945-1976. (Folder 22: 4)
    Includes postcards depicting Perm city in Russia
  - Antonina Yourieff (W. George Yourieff's mother) at Agnews state hospital, 1957-1961 (Folder 22: 5)
- Notes, notebook, prayer book, poetry, 1939 and undated (Folder 22: 6)
- W. George Yourieff's private notes with inscription "Do not open without permission from W. George Yourieff,", 1996 (Folder 22: 7)
- W. George and Alexandra Yourieff general power of attorney, 1983 (Folder 22: 8)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 22: 9)
- Business correspondence, financial documents, photographs, 1955-1997. (Box-folder 23: 1)
  Includes copy of the handwritten draft of will and trust by W. George Yourieff, 1997
- Legal documents, 1960-1970. (Folder 23: 2)
  Includes story "Potato Holiday," written (translated?) by Kirsten A. Seaver, undated
- Alexandra's medical records, 1988 (Folder 23: 3)
- References (mostly business correspondence), 1947-1952, 1991. (Folder 23: 4)
  Includes agreement of durable power of attorney of W. George Yourieff (as a result of the death of his wife Alexandra Yourieff), 1995
- Family correspondence, 1951 (Folder 23: 5)
- Writings--Quisling book. "Quisling's First Wife Dead In the U.S.," translation by Kirsten A. Seaver from Aftenposten (Oslo, Norway) newspaper, 1993 October 5; financial documents, 1976-1977; family correspondence, 1950 (Folder 23: 6)
- Fidelity loan forms, 1974 (Folder 23: 7)
- W. George Yourieff--Business papers, 1964 (Folder 23: 8)
- Clippings, 1948, 1987 (Folder 23: 9)
- Writings--Quisling book. Correspondence with Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States, 1971, and certificate of copyright registration, 1980 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Personal correspondence, 1959, 1979. (Folder 24: 2)
  Includes photographs
- Class notes, 1973 (Folder 24: 3)
- Financial documents (Box 25)
  - 1968 (Folder 25: 1)
  - 1972 (Folder 25: 2-3)
- Mercedes, 1963 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- W. George Yourieff--Day book labeled as diary, 1964-1965 (Folder 26: 2)
- Financial documents
  - 1969 (Folder 26: 3)
  - 1975 (Folder 26: 4)
- California Real Estate Association forms, 1968(?) (Folder 26: 5)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 27: 1)
- Two books of reproductions of Russian icons, 1964, 1969 (Folder 27: 2)
- Daily calendar, 1993 (Folder 27: 3)
- Writings--Quisling book. Album of Alexandra Quisling memorabilia, which includes photographs, cables, and original documents, 1924-1937 (Folder 27: 4)
- Art festivals memorabilia, 1972. (Folder 27: 5)
  Includes one water color painting
- Alexandra Yourieff--Death certificate, 1993 October 1 (Folder 27: 6)
- Photo album, 1923-1925 (Folder 27: 7)
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, 1968-1981 (Folder 27: 8)
- Photographs labeled "Nasha malen'kaia zhizn'" ("Our little life"), undated (Box 28)
- Photo album of Yourieff's family life in China, 1926-1932 (Folder 28: 1)
- Loose photographs, undated (Folder 28: 2)
- W. George Yourieff, 1999. (Folder 28: 3)
  Daybook, obituary, letters of condolence
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 29: 1)
- Irina letters, undated (Folder 29: 2)
- Correspondence, 1983-1999. (Folder 29: 3-4)
- Printouts from websites, 1997 (Folder 29: 5)
- San Francisco Associates (Box 30)
  - General, 1974 (Folder 30: 1-2)
  - W. George Yourieff (personal), 1973-1974 (Folder 30: 3)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Employment records, 1977-1982 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Invitation to attend the inauguration of W. J. Clinton as president of the United States, 1977 January 20 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Corporation papers, 1957-1974 (Folder 30: 6-7)
- France (photographs), undated (Folder 30: 8)
- Auto insurance, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Accident, 1986 January 16 (Folder 31: 2)
- Webster House project, Palo Alto, California, 1985 (Folder 31: 3)
- W. George Yourieff--"My Secret Will,", 1998 (Folder 31: 4)
- Family photographs, undated (Folder 31: 5)
- Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Folder 31: 6)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Business-related material, 1974 (Folder 31: 7)
  - "The precious messages from my dearest friends...,", 1993-1994 (Folder 31: 8)
- Miscellany, 1984-1997 (Folder 31: 9)
- Old insurance, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 32: 1)
- Cadillac, 1977 (Folder 32: 2)
- W. George Yourieff--Business-related material, 1973-1976 (Folder 32: 3-4)
- Family correspondence, 1949-1957 (Folder 32: 5)
- Alex (correspondence), 1949-1964 (Folder 32: 6)
- Tatarinova, Antonina Aleksandrovna, copies of official documents, 1898, 1910 (Folder 32: 7)
- "The Famine in Soviet Russia,", 1979. (Folder 32: 8)
  Photocopy
- Typescript, undated (Folder 32: 9)
- Financial ledgers
  - 1936-1937 (Folder 32: 10)
  - 1951 (Folder 32: 11)
- Miscellany, 1970-1987 (Folder 32: 12)
- Draft of an unidentified writing, undated. (Box-folder 33: 1)
- Writings--Quisling book. Transcription of tapes by Alexandra Voronine Yourieff, book #5 (continuation of tape #15), 1975 (Folder 33: 2)
- University poem, undated. (Folder 33: 3)
  Holograph. In Russian
- Correspondence drafts
  - 1949-1950 (Folder 33: 4)
  - 1950 (Folder 33: 5)
  - 1963-1965 (Folder 33: 6)
- Peking Review, 1978 (Folder 33: 7)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Draft of will, 1955. (Folder 33: 8)
    Holograph
  - Writing draft, undated (Folder 33: 9)
  - Business material, undated (Folder 33: 10)
- Correspondence, 1973, 1987 (Folder 33: 11)
- Miscellany, 1985 (Folder 33: 12)
- Correspondence, 1949-1966 (Box-folder 34: 1)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Diary, 1958 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Writing drafts, 1963-1964 (Folder 34: 3)
  - Certified copy of will and power of attorney, 1989 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1994 (Folder 34: 5)
  - "Tsingtao-San Francisco," draft, book #1, 1949. (Folder 34: 6)
  - Business material, 1992-1993 (Folder 34: 7)
- Yourieff family correspondence, 1950-1983 (Box-folder 35: 1-6)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 36: 1)
- Photo album, undated (Folder 36: 2)
- Drafts of writings
  - undated (Folder 36: 3)
  - 1978 (Folder 36: 4)
- Correspondence
  - General, 1956-1980 (Folder 36: 5)
  - Efimoff, 1952-1961 (Folder 36: 6)
- W. George Yourieff
  - Diary notes, 1910-1929 (Folder 36: 7)
  - Power of attorney, 1989 (Folder 36: 8)
  - Business-related material (Folder 36: 9)
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 36: 10)
- W. George Yourieff (Box 37)
  - Day books
    - 1953 (Folder 37: 1)
    - 1966 (Folder 37: 2)
    - 1972 (Folder 37: 3)
    - 1987-1989 (Folder 37: 4)
      (labeled "Diary")
  - Pocket note/address books, 1996-1997 (Folder 37: 5)
- Photographs, undated (Folder 37: 6)
- Alexandra Yourieff--Will, 1986. (Folder 37: 7)
- Postcards, 1987 (Folder 37: 8)
- Family correspondence, 1954, 1961 (Folder 37: 9)
- Legal documents, 1986 (Folder 37: 10)
- Writings--Quisling book. Alexandra Yourieff--Correspondence, Royal Norwegian Consulate General, 1935, 1982-1983. (Folder 37: 11)
  Includes official documents
- W. George Yourieff--Copy of birth certificate (Folder 37: 12)
- Power of attorney, 1954 (Folder 37: 13)
- Tatarinoff, E. K., correspondence, 1954-1960 (Folder 37: 14)
- Family correspondence regarding attempts to reclaim real estate in China after their arrival in the United States in 1949, 1954-1955 (Folder 37: 15)
- Correspondence (Box 38)
  - General, 1961 (Folder 38: 1)
  - Alex, 1950-1961 (Folder 38: 2)
- Russia file (Folder 38: 3)